<html>
<head>
<title>Downloads</title>
</head>
<body>
<h1>Downloads</h1>
<p>This is the CURSUS Downloads page.  If you want to make substantial use of our resources, 
please contact <a href="mailto:James.Cummings@it.ox.ac.uk">James.Cummings@it.ox.ac.uk</a>. The files are
available in ZIP and TGZ (Tarred GZip) archive formats.  When these files reach a stable 
state, copies of them will be deposited with the 
<a href="http://www.ahds.ac.uk/litlangling/">Arts and Humanities Data Service: Literature, 
Languages and Linguistics</a>, as hosted by the <a href="http://ota.ahds.ac.uk">Oxford Text Archive</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li>
cursus-dtd:
(<a href="/downloads/cursus-dtd.zip">ZIP</a> |  
<a href="/downloads/cursus-dtd.tgz">TGZ</a>)   
This file contains the CURSUS extensions to the TEI P4 DTD.  You will 
need the rest of TEI P4 if you want to use these DTD extensions to validate 
CURSUS texts.  If you are not validating CURSUS texts, you do not need them.
</li>
<li>
cursus-tei-dtd 
(<a href="/downloads/cursus-tei-dtd.zip">ZIP</a> |  
<a href="/downloads/cursus-tei-dtd.tgz">TGZ</a>)  
This file contains the CURSUS extensions bundled with the TEI P4 DTD.
</li>
<li>
cursus-mss 
(<a href="/downloads/cursus-mss.zip">ZIP</a> |  
<a href="/downloads/cursus-mss.tgz">TGZ</a>)  
This file contains the unprocessed XML versions of the CURSUS manuscript 
files.
</li>
<li>
repository 
(<a href="/downloads/repository.zip">ZIP</a> |  
<a href="/downloads/repository.tgz">TGZ</a>)  
This file contains the unprocessed XML of the CURSUS repository 
of antiphons, responds and prayers in CAO and our manscripts.
</li>
<li>
vulgate 
(<a href="/downloads/vulgate.zip">ZIP</a> |  
<a href="/downloads/vulgate.tgz">TGZ</a>)  
This file contains the unprocessed XML of the CURSUS vulgate 
files used as a standardised version for biblical readings 
in our manuscript files.
</li>
<li>
cursus-emacs 
(<a href="/downloads/cursus-emacs.zip">ZIP</a>  | 
<a href="/downloads/cursus-emacs.tgz">TGZ</a>)  
This file contains the CURSUS elisp extensions to EMACS with PGSML 
used to simplify encoding of the other files used by the CURSUS 
project.
</li>
</ul>
</body>
</html>
