<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<samples name="CURSUS Project">
<group name="CURSUS Manuscript Editions">
<note>Editions of the liturgical manuscripts edited by the CURSUS project.  Not all 
of these are complete, and more editions will be forthcoming.  The three letter sigil 
used in the critical editions of antiphons, responds, and prayers is shown in parentheses 
following the manuscript name.  (e.g. Cht = Chertsey)
</note>
<sample href="/ms/chertsey" name="The Chertsey Breviary">The Chertsey Breviary (Cht). Oxford, Bodleian Library Mss lat. liturg. e6, e37, e39 and d42.  </sample>
<sample href="/ms/ely" name="The Ely Breviary-Missal">The Ely Breviary-Missal (Ely).  Cambridge, University Library Ms Ii.4.20.  </sample>
<sample href="/ms/evesham" name="The Evesham Breviary">The Evesham Breviary (Evm). Oxford, Bodleian Library Ms Barlow 41.</sample>
<sample href="/ms/gloucester" name="The Gloucester Diurnal">The Gloucester Diurnal (Glo). Oxford, Bodleian Library MS Jesus College 10.</sample> 
<sample href="/ms/hyde" name="The Hyde Breviary">The Hyde Breviary (Hyd). Oxford, Bodleian Library Ms Rawl.liturg. e.1*.</sample>
<sample href="/ms/peterborough" name="The Peterborough Antiphoner">The Peterborough Antiphoner (Pet). Cambridge, Magdalene College Ms F.4.10.</sample>
<sample href="/ms/winchcombe" name="The Winchcombe Breviary-Missal"> The Winchcombe Breviary-Missal (Wcb).  Valenciennes, Bibl.Mun. Ms 116.</sample>
<sample href="/ms/worcester" name="The Worcester Antiphoner"> The Worcester Antiphoner (Wor). Worcester Cathedral Library Ms F. 160.  </sample>
</group>

<group name="CURSUS Repository of Antiphons, Responds and Prayers">
<note>This section contains allows you to access both the 
critical editions and individual readings for most CAO 
Antiphons and Responds, as well as those that appear in 
the (sections of) manuscripts edited by CURSUS.
</note>
<sample>
If you know the <b>CURSUS ID number</b> of an antiphon respond or prayer
you may enter it here to view a critical edition. (antiphon and 
respond ID numbers start with the letter 'c', prayers with the letter 'o')
If you don't know the ID number of an antiphon, respond or prayer 
you are interested in, you should look in the 
<a href="/incipits/list">incipit list</a> or 
find the item in the manuscript editions.
<form action="/ed-form"> 
<span style="font-weight:bold">ID number:</span> <input width="10" name="id"/>
<input type="submit" />
</form>
</sample>
</group>
<group name="CURSUS Incipit List">
<note>An <a href="/incipits/list">incipit list</a> of all antiphons, responds and prayers found in the 
CURSUS repository is available.  This is divided by these three categories, 
and then alphabetically by first letter (or lacuna).  One incipit is provided 
for each antiphon, respond and prayer, with additional ones for any variant readings 
within the first 10 words.
</note>
<sample name="CURSUS Incipit List" href="/incipits/list">Click for access to CURSUS incipits of 
antiphons, responds and prayers organised alphabetically by first letter.</sample>
 </group>


</samples>
