<html>
<head>
<title>Help (Frequently Asked Questions)</title>
</head>
<body>
<h1>Help (Frequently Asked Questions)</h1>

<h4>Where do I start?</h4>
<p>If you simply want to read through a manuscript look at our 
<a href="/manuscripts">Manuscripts</a> page 
and choose one to begin.  If you know of a particular Antiphon, Respond or 
Prayer Incipit and want to check where in the CURSUS edited manuscripts (and CAO) 
it is used, then you might find our  
<a href="/incipits/list">Incipits</a> list 
of use.  
</p>
  
<h4>Why has the site not been updated?</h4>
<p>The funded project ran from 2000-2003 with occasional updates after that. 
  The project was conceived and lead by Professor David Chadd. During its funded 
  period Dr James Cummings was the research associate and undertook most of the 
  technical aspects of the work as well as some transcription and editing. 
  David continued to work on the transcriptions (and oversaw the implementation of a 
  full-text search facility for the project by Richard Lewis) after the end of the funded period up 
  until his death in November 2006. Around 2010, UEA stopped providing hosting for the project's website. 
  Since then, James Cummings has acquired the data under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International license.
  Any updates after that are purely for maintenance purposes.
</p>
  
<h4>Can I read your copy of the Vulgate?</h4>
<p>Although this copy of the Vulgate was encoded in XML 
only to be used internally to provide the readings for our 
manuscript editions, you may indeed read our copy of the 
<a href="/vulgate">Vulgate</a>.
</p>

<h4>Can I download CURSUS files for my own use?</h4>
<p>Yes, if you want to download the files, the latest versions are
always available in our 
<a href="/downloads">Downloads</a> 
section.  You are allowed to use them for non-commercial use with attribution as they are 
  licensed under a CC+by+nc 4.0 license. If you want to make substantial (or commercial) 
use of them please contact <a href="https://www.twitter.com/jamescummings">James Cummings</a> via twitter.
</p>

<h4>How do I search the files?</h4>
<p>You use our very basic 
<a href="/search">Search</a>
form.  You may search antiphons, responds, prayers, the edited manuscripts, 
or our copy of the vulgate.  Wildcards of '*' for any text and '?' for any 
single missing character are able to be used.
</p>

<h4>Where can I find out more? or Why is my question not here?</h4>
<p> If the web pages do not give you enough information, get in touch <a href="https://www.twitter.com/jamescummings">James Cummings</a> via twitter we will try to help.</p>

</body>
</html>
